[Music]
macrobiotic diets have been described by
the american medical association as one
of the most dangerous dietary regimens
posing not only serious hazards to the
health of the individual but even
to life itself
after all macrobiotic diets are
predominantly vegetarian with a great
emphasis placed on whole grains
what's wrong with that
well they also used to tell people to
not drink water which isn't good and to
avoid fruit
so much so it's resulted in modern day
cases of scurvy
now
thankfully the macrobiotic diet has
evolved over the past 30 years this is
the more kind of contemporary version in
emphasis on whole grains vegetables and
beans while minimizing most meat eggs
and dairy i don't like them restricting
fruits
don't like all the added salt but
compared to the standard american diet
it's got a lot of things going for it
only a quarter of the saturated fat
intake
less than half of the sugar intake a
very respectable fiber intake two and a
half times the national average but
actually taking in
more sodium
so while the macrobiotic diet is an
anti-inflammatory diet has a negative
dietary inflammatory index score as
opposed to the pro-inflammatory american
diet
some of the most anti-inflammatory foods
are herbs and spices so instead of
adding all that sea salt and soy sauce
the macrobiotic diet could be improved
by using natural seasonings instead
okay but has the macrobiotic diet ever
been put to the test yes
for diabetes
the restriction on water probably
wouldn't help as higher plane water
consumption is associated with lower
type 2 diabetes risk though part of that
may be because they're drinking less
soda
and fruit restriction is probably not
helpful since fruit consumption is
associated with significantly reduced
risk of type 2 diabetes as well
but same with green leafy vegetables
which is where the macrobiotic diet can
really shine it includes lots of greens
look you can do randomized double-blind
placebo-controlled crossover studies of
kale
and show that it suppresses the after a
meal increase in blood sugars eat a meal
of white rice chicken and eggs and get a
big spike in blood sugar though
significantly less
adding just a tablespoon of dried kale
powder as opposed to some kind of
placebo powder
though the effect is visually
exaggerated by their y-axis shenanigans
and macrobiotic diets use whole grains
which can significantly improve insulin
sensitivity compared to refined grains
which may be due in part to all the
wonderful things fiber can do to help
our good gut bacteria thrive which could
potentially lower inflammation and
decrease diabetes risk
but you don't know until you
put it to the test
just three weeks on a strictly
plant-based diet composed mostly of
whole grains vegetables and beans and
they got about a 10 drop in blood
pressure a whopping 35 drop in ldl bad
cholesterol and a 38 drop in fasting
blood sugars in just 21 days
were these changes statistically
significant
here's some three-month p-values for you
those are my kind of p-values
in other words yes the changes were
significant in every possible way
similarly short-term interventional
studies on diabetics with the so-called
mapi2 macrobiotic diets have been
performed across four continents the ma
p comes from the guy that came up with
the diet mario pianissi a strictly
plant-based diet based mostly on whole
grains and vegetables with legumes and
some seeds and decaf green tea is the
preferred beverage
look
at these extraordinary numbers a near 40
drop in fasting blood sugars near 27
drop in ldl cholesterol in 21 days
now they did lose weight a few pounds a
week but those kinds of results way more
than one would expect with weight loss
and here's the kicker that 40 drop in
blood sugars was after cutting their
insulin in half
so those numbers greatly underestimate
the effects better results on fewer
drugs that's
the power
of plants all we need now is a
randomized control clinical trial to
really seal the deal
which we'll cover
next
[Music]
foreign